That's it. Get it right to the top.
Steady. Steady.
Up she goes.
Hey, come on. Put your back into it, huh?
Here you are, son.
- Oh, gentlemen, please. - To my right.
And you lot, come on. Come on, get it moving.
Come on, come on.
In all my days I've never seen a man swing an ax like that.
How many men did it take to cut you down?
Just one.
He must have been some kind of monster.
He was a woman.
I think some of the men are a bit afraid of you.
I'm used to it.
When I found you, I thought you'd been dead for days.
The way you were stinking already
and you had bugs all over you
and bone was coming through right there.
I was gonna give you a proper burial and then you coughed.
Oh, nearly shit myself.
I reckoned you were gonna die by the time I loaded you on the wagon,
but you didn't.
Now, I reckoned you'd die a dozen more times over the next few days,
but you didn't. What kept you going?
Hate.
No, there's a reason you're still here.
Aye, there's a reason. I'm a big fucker and I'm tough to kill.
No, a reason.
Gods aren't done with you yet.
I've heard that before.
Man was talking about a different god, though.
Well, maybe he was right.
I don't know much about the gods.
You're in the wrong line of work.
Oh, there's plenty of pious sons of bitches
who think they know the word of god or gods.
I don't. I don't even know their real names.
Maybe it is the Seven. Or maybe it's the old gods.
Or maybe it's the Lord of Light.
Or maybe they're all the same fucking thing.
I don't know.
What matters, I believe,
is that there's something greater than us.
And whatever it is, it's got plans for Sandor Clegane.
You didn't know me back in my time.
You don't know the things I've done.
I've heard stories.
If the gods are real...
why haven't they punished me?
They have.
Your Grace.
What are we reading today?
The Book of the Mother, Your Holiness.
Chapter three, verse 12.
"As water rounds the stones, smoothing--"
"Smoothing what was jagged, so does a woman's love
calm a man's brute nature.
A wife salves her husband's wounds,
a mother sings her son to sleep."
You learn quickly.
There are some who know every verse of the sacred text,
but don't have a drop of the Mother's mercy in their blood
and savages who can't read at all
who understand the Father's wisdom.
For years I pretended to love the poor, the afflicted.
I had pity for them, but I never loved them.
They disgusted me.
They are hard to love.
The poor disgust us because they are us,
shorn of our illusions.
They show us what we'd look like without our fine clothes.
How'd we smell without perfume.
Can I ask you about a personal matter?
Of course.
The king mentioned that since your reunion,
you haven't joined him in the marriage bed.
No.
You have a duty, Your Grace.
To your husband, your king, your country,
to the gods themselves.
It's just...
the desires that once drove me no longer do.
Congress does not require desire
on the woman's part, only patience.
The king must have an heir
if we are to continue our good work.
Forgive me.
Sometimes the true path is hard to find.
Hard to find
and harder still to walk upon.
But you've made great progress.
I only pray your grandmother follows your lead.
My grandmother?
Yes.
The Queen of Thorns is a remarkable woman,
a strong woman,
and an unrepentant sinner.
You must teach her the new way
as she taught you the old.
Or I fear for her safety,
body and soul.
Does it move or talk?
I want to speak with you alone.
Septa Unella has been my true friend and counselor.
Oh, this is madness!
You're not in your sanctuary now, my dear.
All I have to do is whistle
and my men will stroll in here and bash you about...
- Grandmother. - ...until I tell them to stop.
If I tell them to stop.
- You could use a good bashing. - Grandmother, please.
What have they done to you?
You marched against the High Sparrow,
- against the Faith. - We marched for you.
The gods could have punished you and Father, but they didn't.
- They showed mercy. - And what about your brother?
What mercy did they show him?
Loras's only hope is to confess his crimes and repent.
If he does, the Faith will allow him to return to Highgarden.
He'll have to renounce his name and title...
- Have you lost your mind? - ...and live his life as a penitent.
He is the heir to Highgarden, the future of House Tyrell.
He can begin again.
As a mindless fanatic.
As a free man.
You will leave for Highgarden today.
There is no law that says you must stay here.
I am the queen.
It is my duty to serve my husband the king.
But you should leave, Grandmother.
Your place is at home.
I will never leave you. Never.
You must.
Go home.
Find comfort in prayer and good works.
The Mother watches over us all.
I'll see you soon, my dear.
Seven blessings to you, Grandmother.
Shall we pray?
We said we'd fight with you, King Crow,
when the time comes and we meant it,
but this isn't what we agreed to.
These aren't white walkers.
This isn't an army of the dead.
This isn't our fight.
If it weren't for him, none of us would be here.
All of you would be meat in the Night King's army.
And I'd be a pile of charred bones just like Mance.
Remember Mance's camp?
It stretched all the way to the horizon.
And look at us now.
Look what's left of us.
And if we lose this, we're gone.
Dozens of tribes, hundreds of generations.
Be like we were never there at all.
We'll be the last of the free folk.
That's what'll happen to you if we lose.
The Boltons, the Karstarks, the Umbers,
they know you're here.
They know that more than half of you are women and children.
After they finish with me, they'll come for you.
You're right.
This isn't your fight.
You shouldn't have to come to Winterfell with me.
I shouldn't be asking you.
It's not the deal we made.
I need you with me if we're going to beat them,
and we need to beat them if you're going to survive.
The crows killed him because he spoke for the free folk
when no other southerners would.
He died for us.
If we are not willing to do the same for him, we're cowards.
And if that's what we are,
we deserve to be the last of the free folk.
Snow.
Are you sure they'll come?
We're not clever like you southerners.
When we say we'll do something, we do it.
I heard you were leaving King's Landing.
That is hardly your concern.
Your grandson is still a prisoner.
You'll leave him rotting in a cell?
Loras rots in a cell because of you.
The High Sparrow rules this city because of you.
Our two ancient houses face collapse because of you
and your stupidity.
You're right.
I made a terrible mistake.
I carry it with me every single day.
Good.
I delivered an army of fanatics onto our doorstep.
And now we must fight them together.
We need each other.
I wonder if you're the worst person I've ever met.
At a certain age, it's hard to recall.
But the truly vile do stand out through the years.
Do you remember the way you smirked at me
when my grandson and granddaughter were dragged off to their cells?
I do. I'll never forget it.
You love your granddaughter.
I love my son.
It's the only truth I know.
We must defend them.
I'm leaving this wretched city as fast as I can
before that shoeless zealot throws me into one of his cells.
If you're half as bright as you think you are,
you'll find a way out of here, too.
Never.
I'll never leave my son.
What'll you do, then?
You have no support. Not anymore.
Your brother's gone. The High Sparrow saw to that.
The rest of your family have abandoned you.
The people despise you.
You're surrounded by enemies, thousands of them.
You're going to kill them all by yourself?
You've lost, Cersei.
It's the only joy I can find in all this misery.
Pick the pace up.
Keep going.
Keep it moving!
Now, that is a sorry attempt at a siege.
Someone needs to teach those sad twats how to dig trenches.
Someone certainly does.
Oh, no. Not me.
I'm just an upjumped sellsword.
You're an anointed knight. There's quite a difference.
Aye, knights don't get paid.
You have better instincts than any officer
in the Lannister army.
That's like saying I have a bigger cock
than anyone in the Unsullied army.
I expect to command all the Lannister forces before long.
You can be the right hand I lost.
You promised me a lordship and a castle
and a highborn beauty for a wife.
And you'll get all three. A Lannister always--
Don't say it. Don't fucking say it.
Come out and fight us, Blackfish.
We have Lord Edmure.
Yield the castle or we'll hang him.
This is your last warning.
Yield the castle.
You think I won't do it, old man?
I sliced your niece's throat from ear to ear.
And where were you? Running and hiding like a fucking coward.
Yield the castle or I cut his throat.
Go on, then. Cut his throat.
Lothar, is it?
Ser Jaime.
We didn't know you were coming.
'Cause you didn't set a proper perimeter.
You just allowed 8,000 men to approach unchallenged.
Good thing we're friends
or we'd be fucking you in the ass right now.
Have Lord Edmure bathed and fed.
Walder.
Edmure is a prisoner of House Frey.
Only a fool makes threats he's not prepared to carry out.
Now let's say I threatened to hit you
unless you shut your mouth, but you kept talking.
- What do you think I'd do? - I don't give a rat's--
I'm here by the king's command to take back this castle.
Have him bathed and fed.
Unless you'd like to take his place.
Apologies, Ser Jaime.
Do as he says.
The siege is now under my command.
The next time the Blackfish looks out from those ramparts,
he'll see an army at his gates, not whatever this is.
Have your lads start digging perimeter trenches.
Set pickets every hundred yards.
And work double-time on those siege towers and trebuchets.
Those are our siege towers--
As I said, the siege is under my command.
If that's not to your liking, go home.
Get word to the Blackfish.
I want a parley.
A parley or a fight?
He's an old man.
You've got one hand.
My money's on the old boy.
Lady Mormont.
Welcome to Bear Island.
I remember when you were born, my lady.
You were named for my Aunt Lyanna.
It was said she was a great beauty. I'm sure you will be, too.
I doubt it. My mother wasn't a great beauty
or any other kind of beauty.
She was a great warrior, though.
She died fighting for your brother Robb.
I served under your uncle at Castle Black, Lady Lyanna.
He was also a great warrior and an honorable man.
I was his steward. In fact--
I think we've had enough small talk. Why are you here?
Stannis Baratheon garrisoned at Castle Black
before he marched on Winterfell and was killed.
He showed me the letter you wrote to him
when he petitioned for men.
- It said-- - I remember what it said.
Bear Island knows no king but the King in the North
whose name is Stark.
Robb is gone,
but House Stark is not.
And it needs your support now more than ever.
I've come with my sister to ask for House Mormont's allegiance.
As far as I understand, you're a Snow
and Lady Sansa is a Bolton.
Or is she a Lannister?
I've heard conflicting reports.
I did what I had to do to survive, my lady.
But I am a Stark. I will always be a Stark.
If you say so. In any case,
you don't just want my allegiance. You want my fighting men.
Ramsay Bolton cannot be allowed to keep Winterfell, my lady.
It is our duty to stop him.
Even more so because he holds our brother Rickon Stark as prisoner.
What you have to understand, my lady, is that--
I understand that I'm responsible for Bear Island
and all who live here.
So why should I sacrifice
one more Mormont life for someone else's war?
If it please, my lady,
I understand how you feel.
I don't know you, Ser...?
Davos, my lady, of House Seaworth.
You needn't ask your maester about my house.
It's rather new.
All right, Ser Davos of House Seaworth.
How is it you understand how I feel?
You never thought you'd find yourself in your position.
Being responsible for so many lives at such a young age.
I never thought I'd be in my position.
I was a crabber's son, then I was a smuggler.
And now I find myself addressing the lady of a great house
in time of war.
But I'm here because this isn't someone else's war.
It's our war.
Go on, Ser Davos.
Your uncle, Lord Commander Mormont,
made that man his steward.
He chose Jon to be his successor because he knew
he had the courage to do what was right,
even if it meant giving his life.
Because Jeor Mormont and Jon Snow both understood
that the real war isn't between a few squabbling houses.
It's between the living and the dead.
And make no mistake, my lady,
the dead are coming.
Is this true?
Your uncle fought them at the Fist of the First Men.
I fought them at Hardhome.
We both lost.
As long as the Boltons hold Winterfell, the North is divided.
And a divided North won't stand a chance against the Night King.
You want to protect your people, my lady. I understand.
But there's no hiding from this.
We have to fight and we need to do it together.
House Mormont has kept faith with House Stark for 1,000 years.
We will not break faith today.
Thank you, my lady.
How many fighting men can we expect?
62.
- 62? - We are not a large house,
but we're a proud one.
And every man from Bear Island
fights with the strength of 10 mainlanders.
If they're half as ferocious as their lady,
the Boltons are doomed.
Kingslayer.
Blackfish.
I assume you're here
to fulfill the vow you gave my niece.
I don't see Sansa and Arya.
- I don't have them. - Pity.
Do you wish to resume your captivity?
Then why are you here?
You know why I'm here.
This castle belongs to House Frey.
You're trespassing.
In the name of King Tommen, I order you to surrender or--
Or you'll kill Edmure?
My nephew's marked for death no matter what.
Hang him and be done with it.
It won't stop with Edmure.
You'll force me to storm the castle.
Hundreds will die.
Hundreds of mine. Thousands of yours.
If you can breach the walls.
We'll breach them and kill every last one of you.
But if you surrender,
I'll spare the lives of your men.
On my honor.
Your honor?
Bargaining with oathbreakers is like building on quicksand.
The war is over, ser.
Why sacrifice living men to a lost cause?
As long as I'm standing, the war is not over.
This is my home.
I was born in this castle and I'm ready to die in it.
So you can either attack
or try to starve us out.
We have enough provisions for two years.
Do you have two years, Kingslayer?
You clearly have no intention of saving your men's lives.
Why did you come treat with me?
Sieges are dull.
And I wanted to see you in person, get the measure of you.
Well, now you have.
Aye, now I have.
I'm disappointed.
The answer is no.
- Lord Glover, if you could just hear us out. - I've heard enough.
We've only just taken back this castle from the ironborn.
The Boltons helped us do it.
Now you want me to fight against them?
I could be skinned for even talking to you.
The Boltons are traitors. Roose Bolton--
Have other northern houses pledged to fight for you?
House Mormont.
And?
We sent ravens to Houses Manderly--
I don't care about ravens.
You're asking me to join your army.
Who is fighting in this army?
The bulk of the force is made up of wildlings.
Then the rumors are true.
I didn't dare believe them.
I received you out of respect for your father.
Now I would like you to leave.
House Glover will not abandon its ancestral home
to fight alongside wildlings.
- Lord Glover. - There's nothing else to say.
I would remind you that House Glover
is pledged to House Stark.
Sworn to answer when called upon.
Yes, my family served House Stark for centuries.
We wept when we heard of your father's death.
When my brother was lord of this castle,
he answered Robb's call and hailed him King in the North.
And where was King Robb
when the Ironborn attacked this castle?
When they threw my wife and children in prison
and brutalized and killed our subjects?
Taking up with a foreign whore.
Getting himself and those who followed him killed.
I served House Stark once,
but House Stark is dead.
Why did we have to come here?
Some of us still like it.
Have a drink at least.
I don't want one.
Don't go far, love.
I'll find you in a bit.
Nothing on the Iron Islands has an ass like that.
Doesn't interest you anymore?
I'm sorry. I won't joke about it.
I'll never hurt you, little brother.
Don't you know that?
You think Uncle Euron's hunting for us?
Of course he is. As long as we're alive, we're a threat.
He'll find us.
It's a great big world and we have fast ships.
Drink.
I don't want any.
I don't care what you want. Drink.
Drink it all.
You're Ironborn, Theon. I know you've had some bad years.
Some bad years?
But I'm tired of watching you cower like a beat dog.
Drink the goddamn ale.
Now listen to me.
I need you.
The real Theon Greyjoy,
not this rat shit pretender.
Can you find him for me?
Drink.
You escaped. You hear me?
You got away and you're never going back.
We'll get justice for you.
If I got justice,
my burnt body would hang over the gates of Winterfell.
Fuck justice, then. We'll get revenge. Drink.
Listen to me.
If you're so broken that there's no coming back,
take a knife and cut your wrists.
End it.
But if you're staying, Theon, I need you.
We're gonna sail to Meereen.
We're gonna make a pact with this Dragon Queen.
And we're gonna take back the Iron Islands.
Are you with me?
Are you really with me?
Now, since it's my last night ashore for a long while,
I'm gonna go fuck the tits off this one.
Stannis camped here on his way to Winterfell.
And that's a good thing?
He was the most experienced commander in Westeros.
He chose this place for a reason.
Those mountains are a natural fortification.
There's a stream down there for the horses.
We're not staying here long.
Another storm could hit any day.
Aye, the snows defeated Stannis
as much as the Boltons did.
We have to march on Winterfell now while we still can.
2,000 wildlings,
200 Hornwoods, 143 Mazins--
62 Mormonts.
It's not what we'd hoped for.
But we still have a chance if we're careful and smart.
For fuck's sake.
So he's your most trusted advisor now?
Because he secured 62 men from a 10-year-old?
Ser Davos is the reason I'm standing here talking to you
and he served Stannis for years.
Stannis who lost the Blackwater,
who murdered his own brother, who doesn't have a head?
It's not enough. We need more men.
There's no time.
If we went down to Castle Cerwyn, I know that Lord--
We fight with the army we have.
Friends, this is not worth fighting over!
This'll be it, now.
Right, now we don't need to be fighting--
- Who the fuck are you? - Hold on.
Yeah, who the fuck are you?
I was a soldier once.
All my superiors thought I was brave.
I wasn't. I mean, I never ran from a fight.
Only because I was afraid my friends would see I was afraid.
That's all I was, a coward.
We followed orders no matter the orders.
Burn that village.
Fine, I'm your arsonist.
Steal that farmer's crops. Good, I'm your thief.
Kill those young lads so they won't take up arms against us.
I'm your murderer.
I remember once a woman screaming at us,
calling us animals as we dragged her son from their hut.
But we weren't animals.
Animals are true to their nature
and we had betrayed ours.
I cut that young boy's throat myself
as his mother screamed
and my friends held her back.
That night...
I felt such shame.
Shame was so heavy on me,
I couldn't eat, I couldn't sleep.
All I could do was stare into that dark sky
and listen to that mother screaming her son's name.
I'll hear her screaming the rest of my life.
Now, I know I can never bring that lad back.
All I can do with time I've got left
is bring a little goodness into the world.
That's all any of us can do, isn't it?
Never too late to stop robbing people,
to stop killing people.
Start helping people.
It's never too late to come back.
And it's not about waiting for the gods to answer your prayers.
It's not even about the gods. It's about you.
Learning you have to answer your prayers yourself.
Seven save you, friends.
How can we help you?
What are you doing here?
Well, we're talking about life.
You?
Protecting the people.
Well, we thank you for your protection.
Who are you protecting us from?
Do you have any horses?
No horses.
No gold. No steel.
Food, then. Protecting the people is hungry work.
I'm sure it is.
You're welcome to stay for supper,
but we have hungry mouths here.
Stay safe.
The night is dark and full of terrors.
"Seven save you, friends."
I'm a fucking septon. What was I supposed to say?
They don't believe in your Seven.
They're from the Brotherhood. They follow the Red God.
Aye, well, all are welcome here.
Anyway, we got nothing for them.
Sure, you do. You've got food,
you've got steel even if you say you don't.
And you've got women.
What do you want to do? Fight them?
Kill them?
It'd be you against all of them.
I mean, these people don't know how to fight.
You do.
I'm done with fighting.
Even if it's to protect yourself?
Violence is a disease.
You don't cure a disease by spreading it to more people.
You don't cure it by dying, either.
You've done enough work for one day.
Come on up for some supper.
It's gonna be a cold night.
We'll need firewood.
I'll save you a bowl of stew.
Might even have some ale hidden away.
He's not a lying man.
He says the Iron Fleet's in Slaver's Bay.
I'm inclined to believe him.
I'm not going anywhere near those mad fuckers.
You're Westerosi.
What do you care?
I want to book passage home.
You? Can't afford it.
Where'd you steal this from?
Why do you care?
We leave in two days.
You can have a hammock in steerage.
I want a cabin.
And we'll leave at dawn.
See you at sunrise.
Sweet girl.